

Justine Meyr

Offering twenty years of domestic and international experience in the field of Education. I hold a PhD in Education, and am accomplished as a multilingual creator of engaging educational content, director, and researcher. I am a self-starter who is particularly interested in social impact and understands the importance of good communication, flexibility and a collaboration in a diverse work environment.

justinemeyr@gmail.com

(510) 717 – 3349



Santa Barbara

https://www.linkedin.com/in/justine-meyr-0a2150133

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Director of Science and Letters, Make School, San Francisco, CA. 2020 – 2021

Startup university offering a BA in Computer Science. I designed implemented and taught several GE requirements. Collaborated in fully online environments with multiple team members and our partner university, including stakeholders, for profit companies, tech leaders, students and bay area high schools. Created online, bichronous and blended learning classes. Hired and supported faculty. Worked in conjunction with DEI administrator to create workshops to ensure for inclusive curriculum across disciplines. COURSES TAUGHT: ENGLISH EC2, WRITING EC1 and TECHNOLOGY AND EQUITY

Accomplishments: Designed, implemented and evaluated 6 new GE courses, built and maintained relationships with stakeholders and leadership, hired and supervised 8 faculty members, used data analysis and OKRs to measure goals and track outcome, and created online inclusive curriculum.

Lecturer of Spanish and German, University of California, Santa Barbara, CA 2018 – 2020

Curriculum and materials development, instructional design, assessment, placement tests, TA development, a/synchronous instruction, continued research in computer assisted language learning and technology in Education. COURSES TAUGHT: GERMAN 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and 8c; SPANISH 2, 3, 6, 2HY.

Accomplishments: Presented at three conferences and attended several EdTech conferences in the U.S. Developed materials for an open source textbook which was integrated into the learning management system. Completed research using mixed methods. Implemented varying methodologies and publishing tools in instruction. Designed curriculum for online, face-to-face and blended learning.

Teaching/Research Assistant, University of California, Santa Barbara, CA 2012 – 2017

Instructed classes, developed curriculum and assessment tools, specialized in digital learning and technology integration, used learning management system and Facebook to build learning communities, conducted surveys, interviews and ethnographic and action research to inform pedagogical practices.

COURSES TAUGHT: BLACK STUDIES 45, 60; SPANISH 1, 2, 3; GERMAN 1, 2, 3; EDUCATION 289

Accomplishments: Presented an attended educational conference in US and Europe, published one article, assisted in the development of a pronunciation app for android, led workshops in curriculum design and technology integration training in language courses. Created DEI content for language and social studies courses.

Project Manager/Learning Strategist, Ransom Seed Laboratory, Carpinteria, CA 2010 – 2012

Implemented and facilitated the development of a new computer program. Worked as a liaison between the business owner and programmer to develop an online program to suit business needs and work processes.

Accomplishments: Developed performance support strategies and learning delivery strategies for 13 employees. Trained, supervised and supported staff in daily business operations with the new computer program. Created instructional materials and work manuals.

AREAS OF EXPERIENCE

Intercultural /Interpersonal Skills DEI Curriculum People Management

Project Management Public Speaking Learning Content Management **Mixed Methods Research Adult Learning Strategies** Leadership

TECHNOLOGY - *Platforms:* Windows & MAC OSX Operating systems. *Software:* Microsoft Office, Google Drive, QuickBooks, PeopleSoft, GitHub, Asana, Outlook, Zoom, Slack, Canvas, and various Learning Management systems *Graphics:* Adobe Creative Suite.

LANGUAGES – English (native speaker), Spanish (near native speaker), German (high intermediate), Italian (intermediate), Portuguese (basic).

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Education, The Gevirtz School of Education, University of California, Santa Barbara 2017

- o Emphasis: Applied Linguistics, Cultural Perspectives and Comparative Education
- Dissertation: Building a Community of Inquiry in a Telecollaboration between U.S. and German University Students, https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED584384
- o Visiting Scholar for academic year 2015-16 at Albert Ludwig University, Freiburg im Breisgau, Germany

MA, Latin American and Iberian Studies. University of California Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA 2010

- o Emphasis: International Education/Language Acquisition
- o Thesis: Spanish Language Maintenance in Returnee UCEAP Students

Certificate of Business Administration. UC Berkeley Extension, Berkeley, CA 2006

BA, major History and Italian Language, minor Economics. Brandeis University, Waltham, MASS 2002

Study Abroad in Italy: NYU Florence (Summer), Business School (SAA) Turin (Fall), University of Siena (Spring)

AWARDS, SERVICE AND LEADERSHIP

- ✓ UCSB German and Slavic Studies Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award 2015
- UCSB Graduate Student Association Excellence in Teaching Award in the Social Sciences 2014
- ✓ UCSB Workshops in Second Language Acquisition. 2013-2015 Planned, advertised and presented University workshops for language teachers at UCSB. Workshops focused on department collaborations, current issues in language pedagogy, and teaching new technology skills to instructors of foreign languages.
- ✓ UNICEF: United Nations Children's Fund, Intern, Santiago, Chile 2002

 Volunteer for extracurricular program development in underprivileged neighborhoods in urban areas.

RESEARCH, PRESENTATIONS AND PUBLICATIONS

- ✓ Modern Language Association (MLA), Poster Presentation on Open Source Portuguese textbook, Seattle, Washington, University of Washington. 2020
- ✓ Meyr, J. & Viana da Silva, E. (under review for 2020). Intercultural Communication and Attitudes of Openness. *Portuguese Language Journal*.
- ✓ AATSP (American Association of Teachers of Spanish and Portuguese) SoCal, Presenter, Santa Barbara, CA UCSB. 2018
- ✓ SWALLT/NWALL (South/North West Association for Language Learning), Presenter, Seattle, Washington, University of Washington. 2018
- ✓ *Journal of Virtual Exchange* (JVE), Copy Editor. Copy editing for a research journal in learning languages with technology. (https://journal.unicollaboration.org). 2017-2020
- ✓ Chun, D., Jiang, Y., Meyr, J. & Yang, R. (2015). Acquisition of L2 Mandarin Chinese tones with learner-created tone visualizations. *Journal of Second Language Pronunciation*, 1(1). John Benjamins Publishing Company.
- ✓ CALICO, Presenter, Honolulu, Hawaii, University of Hawaii Phonetics research on the acquisition of Chinese tones via PRAAT in L2 Chinese learners. 2013
- ✓ Language Learning and Technology, Copy Editor. Copy editing for a research journal in language and technology (<a href="http://ht